A day wasted

Day 00178: Tuesday, 2015 September 01

My siblings and I planned to head out into town again today in hopes of getting further than last time, but it didn't work out. Our mother needed help with her classroom again, which was all well and good, but she wouldn't give us a straight answer about when she wanted us home by to meet here. She insisted that in order to give us the most possible time so we could go the furthest possible in that time, she would pick us up at wherever we ended up by the time she needed help. She does not seem to understand the fact that we, and I in particular, do not like to get picked up. Getting picked up is an unnecessary waste of fossil fuels. Not knowing how long we had, we couldn't go far. We didn't feel we had time to even make it as far as we did last time, let alone make it further. And with everything useful seeming to be in a single direction, there wasn't really much we could do. Though I don't think she understands it, her plan to give us more time backfired and took away what time we would have had if she would have just been reasonable and told us when she wanted to meet up by.

What little we could have gotten done today had just become impossible, so we decided to give up trying to find anything useful and set out in another direction, this time not leaving the residential area. We gave ourselves one and a half hours, at which point we would head home and hope to get back before we were needed. We ended up spending most of the time with three chickens that we found. I mostly just watched, but my siblings tried feeding the chickens various things. The thing they most seemed to like were blackberries plucked from a nearby bush. They seemed nervous around us at first, but calmed down a bit when they saw we weren't coming after them. They even came over and pecked at us gently a bit.

We made it home in time, then headed over to the school with our mother. Apparently, the school has Wi-Fi, though I hadn't known that before. I could have brought my laptop in to update my website while we were there if only I had known. At least now I know for next time.

I received an email stating that Cricket's $5 USD charged to my credit card finally finalized. I don't know if this will impact the process of getting Cricket Wireless to reverse the charge and give me back the money. We're headed back to Springfield tomorrow, so I might get a chance to talk to Cricket support then. Or maybe not, we'll see how much time there is and what is on the agenda.

I am cut off from the Internet tonight, and cannot update my warrant canary.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

At my old residence for the night

Day 00179: Wednesday, 2015 September 02

We set out this morning to our old residence. On the way, I received an email saying that my last paycheck from my old job was available, and asking whether I would be in town to pick it up at some point or if I had an address I would like it forwarded to. I replied that the timing on that letter was funny, as I was on the road to Springfield already. Apparently though, the secretary had not expected me to opt to pick it up. She wasn't supposed to give it to me until the fifth of the month, but figured that is would be fine to mail it now because it would take longer than that to reach me. Because she had already offered to let me pick it up though, she allowed me to take it as long as I promised not to deposit it until the fifth at 16:00.

I contacted Cricket support, who said that they would not give me a refund on the $5 USD I had put on my account. I contacted Cricket immediately a second time to get a different representative, and the conversation went on longer. The second person first tried to convince me to stay with Cricket. WHen that didn't work, she said that there was no way to get a refund and tried to get me to spend the account credit on one of two Cricket add-on services, both of which cost more than the account credit is worth, so I would have to hand Cricket even more money. The first add-on was an extra data package, but Cricket already gives me more high-speed data than I use. Even if they didn't, they offer unlimited low-speed data, and most on my data use is just for background stuff such as email, so I don't need it to go quickly. The second was a music service that streams proprietary music using a proprietary application that is only available from Google Play, which is not even installed on my device. I could pay for the service, but the service is not one I have any interest in and not one I could even make use of if I did have interest in it. Lastly, she handed over a postal address where I could send complaints. I'm going to be cut off from the Internet again for a while, so I think I'll type up a complaint letter as I have time, then when I have access to a printer, print and mail the thing. I need to mention both the no-refunds policy and the canceled orders.

My mother wants to close our Internet service account at our former residence, but she uses our ISP's email option, and she has a lot of old letters saved. We started backing them up, but there are a lot of them, and we couldn't finish tonight.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Bringing the cat

Day 00180: Thursday, 2015 September 03

Between the fact that the router kept failing and the sheer number of emails she has on the ISP server, we didn't have time to finish backing up my mother's email. We'll have to try again next time we have Internet access.

It took some effort, but we managed to load up the washer and dryer loaded up onto the trailer to take with us. It's been kind of lame not being able to do laundry. Once we got them home though, we found that the dryer has a plug type that doesn't match the electrical outlet at the home we're renting. We might be able to swap out the dryer cord later, but until then, we still can't wash our clothing.

The other main thing we took with us back home was our cat. My mother had left the cat before for a couple reasons. First, until the move is complete, there are going to be long periods of time when everyone is out. My mother thought it would be kinder to the cat to leave her in a familiar place alone than leave her in an unfamiliar place alone. Second, the older of my two sisters didn't come with us, so my mother thought it would be nice to leave the cat as company for my sister for a while. My mother seems oblivious to the fact that the cat and my sister are mostly indifferent to one another. When we got to our former residence though, it was very clear that the cat was lonely, so she decided she should come with us on this trip. We spend more time at home than at our old residence, so the cat should be less lonely there, despite the fact that her whole environment has changed.

On the trip home, the cat seemed nervous, but not panicky. She spent most of the trip sitting on my younger sister's lap, seemingly wanting comfort from a familiar person, but otherwise seemed very calm. Once home, we walked the cat through every room of the house to try to get her familiar with it, after which she went and hid under my bed. She didn't seem to mind my brother and I coming under with her, but she did not want to leave.

I am cut off from the Internet tonight and cannot update my warrant canary.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Lots of mobile issues

Day 00181: Friday, 2015 September 04

When I awoke this morning, I found that instead of still being under my bed, our cat was not on top of the bed with me. Since then, she has moved around the bed a bit, and occasionally leaves it, but even when left alone, she continues to mostly gravitate towards the bed.

For quite a while, I've wanted to disable the "Phone" application on my mobile, but the usual interface for disabling system applications doesn't allow this. When looking at the "Phone" application in the system menu, the option to disable it is greyed out. I've been told that there is a way to disable any such application from the command line, but had yet to look into it until today. Because I wanted to be home as much as possible while the cat gets used to her residence, I didn't really have anything productive to work on. I looked up instructions telling me that to list packages, I should run pm list packages and to disable a package, I should run "pm disable {package name}" as root. I tried disabling com.android.phone that way, but it did not work. Instead of removing the "Phone" icon from the application drawer, it removed it from the system menu but left it in the application drawer, still usable. After fiddling with it a bit and rebooting several times, I decided that the only way to disable the calling functionality was probably to outright delete the "Phone" application. I decided to install "/system/app mover", move the "Phone" application to where I could back it up and delete it, back it up, then uninstall it. However, upon moving the application, complications arose. First, the "Phone" application crashed, popping up a dialog asking for confirmation of the message. That didn't seem so unexpected, as it had just gotten moved. However, every time I confirmed the message, it would pop back up again! It seemed the "Phone" application insisted on restarting. No matter how many times it crashed, it would not stay down. I tried rebooting the device, as it was the only thing I could do with the device in that state. After rebooting, "Phone" crashed once, then stayed down. However, the GSM signal icon had disappeared entirely! It seems the "Phone" application is somehow tied to the wireless capabilities of the device. I find this particularly frustrating because Android tablets do not have the "Phone" application, yet they still connect to the network. For some reason, the "Phone" application is necessary for connection, but only on so-called "phones".

Undoing the move of the "Phone" application was not easy. "/system/app mover" could not find the application to move it back, so I had to do it manually. First, I verified that the two application directories were located at /system/app and /data/app. Then, I tried using the mv command. It shouldn't be very hard, right? Wrong. mv failed due to the two directories existing on different partitions. I tried cp, but that didn't work either. This time, the problem was that the /system partition is read-only. I tried running mount --help for a hint as to how to remount the system as writable, but the command wouldn't take the --help flag or the -h flag. I couldn't look up the answer online because I had no connection; my laptop was offline due to not having an ISP and my mobile was offline due to this mess I caused and was trying to clean up. I tried running mount --help on my laptop to see if instructions existed there, but the instructions there were incomplete. There was no mention whatsoever about remounting. I cobbled together mount -o remount,rw from part of the --help output with some broken fragments of information in my own memory, and tried running that.

When messing around with the mobile, one thing I did was turn on "fixed dialing numbers". I don't know what those do yet, but it seems that that feature is buggy and messes with connectivity as well. If fixed dialing numbers are turned on when the device boots, connectivity will not be available until the feature is turned back off. However, when the feature is first turned on, connectivity will not be lost right away. Instead, no issue will be seen until the next time the device restarts. The connectivity issues caused by that took much longer to solve, though I didn't actively try to figure them out the whole time because I had no way to know if the issues were caused by my device or caused by the carrier's towers.

It seems that some scammer got ahold of a bunch of my mother's personal information, including her full legal name, telephone number, and the last four digits of her Social Security number. He called her up claiming to be the IRS, saying that she had accidentally committed fraud on her taxes or something. He claimed that the IRS had audited her taxes, and she owned them money. If she wouldn't pay, he said that the IRS would take her to court. When she refused to pay, not believing he was with the real IRS, he claimed that an officer would be be at her door in forty-five minutes to put her in handcuffs for a really, really long time. Yeah. Right. That sounds very legitimate. Of course, the officer never showed up because there wasn't any real legal issues going on.

At our new residence, we've got a greenhouse full of edible plants and some corn stalks growing outside it. The landlord said we can take whatever vegetables we want from there, and that many of them are ready to harvest. Today, we tried opening up some of the corn ears and found that they are not the generic yellow that we expected. Instead, the corn is a variety of fun colors. Most of it is varying shades of green and purply-grey, but there are also reds, purples, and a few standard yellow mixed in. Each kernel, even on one cob, seems to be a different color, aside from the yellow ones which all matched. The cobs themselves are still yellow, as are the sides of the kernels that are not directly exposed before removing kernels from the cob. It's unfortunate that corn kernels are so attached to the cob that removing them seems to damage them. Once I have Internet access back up on my laptop, I plan to do some research on how to safely remove corn kernels for planting. It would be fun to keep this atypical corn around.

I am cut off from the Internet tonight and cannot update my warrant canary.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

They want note from my mother!?

Day 00185: Tuesday, 2015 September 08

Today my brother and I set out for South Coast Ilwu Credit Union, the credit union my sister and I tried to go to two days ago. We got there half an hour before they opened, so we had some time to rest. When it opened, we found out that membership is only available to members of workers' unions in the area and their family members. I had forgotten that credit unions have arbitrary membership requirements such as these. Luckily, my mother had mentioned having to join the teachers' union a few days ago, so I knew she was a member of that. I told the representative that our mother was a member of the teachers' union, and we moved to the next step: asking about fees. It turns out that while I could join that credit union, withdrawing from a savings account too many times causes fees to be charged. Furthermore, starting a checking account, which has no such restrictions attached, costs $100 USD. I found this to be unreasonable, so I thanked the representative for her time and we left.

We went to the next-closest credit union, which was a long way from home: Oregon First Community Credit Union. Once we got there, the representative told me that none of the specific fees I asked about existed at that credit union, and transfered me to a higher-level representative to create my account. This representative said that my old residence did not meet this credit union's residency requirements and I would have to prove my new address to them. After all, my state-issued ID says I live in Springfield. She updated my record at the DMV to use my new address, which I didn't even know she could do. I asked her about it, and it seems that anyone having my DMV ID number and my date of birth, both of which she got from looking at my ID, can update my DMV ID record. That's kind of scary, but now the DMV will supposedly be sending me a correction sticker to put on my ID to amend my address. After talking a while, I explained that I do not receive mail under my legal name, so I would not be able to use a letter to my house as proof of anything concerning my legal identity. She asked about bank statements, and I explained that all my statements are sent by email, not postal mail. I asked if I could send her one of the credit card statements to her email box, but she said that the representatives are unable to accept outside email. However, she said that if I went and printed it out, I could use it as proof of my new address. She was also unsure if the account could be created since I don't have a telephone number, but said she would talk to her boss about it while I went out to find a printer.

Next, we headed down to the public library, which was an entirely different direction from home that the credit union. On the way there, we saw a pawn shop with bicycles out front. One was missing a chain, but was only $25 USD! My bicycle with the bent wheel has a working chain, so between the two of them, I might be able to get a working bike. I may be back to buy this bike later.

Finally, we made it to the library. There, I learned that printing cost $0.2 USD per sheet. I sat down at one of the computers, and to my delight, the machine was running Ubuntu! I mean, Ubuntu is no Debian, it's full of proprietary gunk, but it's *way* better than the Windows operating system I expected to see. Unfortunately, like Debian, does not seem to have the software needed to speak with mobile devices installed by default. And like any Debian-based system, the administrative password would have been needed in order to install it. I ended up downloading the run-in-place Tor Browser Bundle, using it to access the Discover website, and copying my password by hand from the KeePassX/KeePassDroid database on my mobile to log in. I though the statement was four pages long, and I thought I would only need the first page which had my address on it, but for added authenticity, I printed the whole thing. If the credit union wanted more, I didn't want to have to come back to the library. It turns out that the PDF credit card statement was longer than I thought it was in my hasty glance over the document. It was actually six pages long, though the librarian gave me the last page gratis due to it having only one line of text on it.

While I was there, I decided to ask about the requirements for getting a library card there. I'm going to be in the area a while, so it might be nice to be able to check out books sometimes. She said I needed proof of address and photo ID, but nothing else. I showed her the credit card statement that she had just sold me as proof of address, along with my state-issued ID card, and she gave me a form to fill out. She was surprised that I don't have a telephone number, but this did not prevent her from opening the account for me. She mentioned that I might want to insert my middle initial in the signature spot on the library card due to there already being a client with my first and last name on record, but that I didn't have to. I added it, then replied that I wasn't too concerned and I don't even go by my legal name anyway. She asked about the name I use, which I gave her, and she asked if I wanted that name on the account. Surprised that she could do this, I happily accepted, but it turns out my legal name is on the account too. Additionally, she was not able to use my preferred last name. My library account now has me listed as "Yst {legal last name}". No worries though, that's more than I had dared hope for, and I care more about the name "Yst" than the name "Dawson".

Though not relevant to much today, I do have a few more notes about the library. They sell USB drives, for one thing. This got me thinking about my own USB drives at home. Normally, I can't use my own USB drives away from home. The problem is that other peoples' computers run Windows, which cannot read ext4 file systems. It's bad enough that FAT file systems are known for fragmentation and file corruption. However, what I really can't stand is FAT's complete lack of case sensitivity. This is something that I will not tolerate in a file system. As a result, I end up with removable media (USB drives, SD cards, et cetera) that work only on computers that can read ext4 file systems. But the library is using Ubuntu on its machines. Than means that while they may not be able to read files off my mobile (due to lack of installed software, not a flaw in Ubuntu), they *can* read my USB drives from home! If I know I will need a file at the library, I can prepare by transferring it to a USB drive. Second, they also sell blank CDs, though I wouldn't know what to do with those. I mean, I know how to burn them, I just don't know why I would want to in most cases. The final thing that the library sells is ear buds. They refuse to lend any out; they have posted a notice explaining that they can't do this as multiple people using the same ear buds is not safe. This is of no consequence to me, as I can't stand having sound directly in my ear like that anyway, but it amuses me none the less. Speaking of lending objects otherwise for sale, the library does lend USB drives for in-library use only. As for the library's actual book-lending services, it seems that all the libraries in Coos County are interconnected. Using one library card, you may borrow a book from one library and return it at another. Likewise, you may check out books at the local collage's library with that same card. As one final note, the desktop used by the library computers is Mate. I don't have any strong opinions about Mate, but it's a reasonable desktop under a reasonable license.

In what felt to me like the longest leg of our journey, my brother and I headed back to Oregon First Community Credit Union. Once there, I sat down with a representative to get the account set up, though it was a different representative than last time. This representative said that I could not use the credit card statement as proof of address. Instead, I would need to get a note from my mother that included my address, her telephone number, the fact that I live at this address, and her signature. Really? Really!? This representative would not accept a credit card statement from a well-known bank (Discover), but *would* accept a note from my mother? First of all, I'm old enough to flash my ID and legally buy alcohol (not that I've ever done that). I'm certainly old enough not to need my mother to write me notes for things or even be involved in setting up my financial accounts. Not to mention the obvious flaw in such a setup: I could forge the note myself. With the credit card statement, there's a lot more trustworthiness than a note from a parent. I tried explaining this, but the representative was adamant. With clear frustration, I thanked her for her time, and said that I was not going to be bringing a note from my mother, and that if that is what it took, I would seek an account elsewhere. She actually recommended Sterling, which I'm fairly certain is a bank! Why would a credit union representative be recommending a bank? She next said that if I changed my mind, to come back with the parental note, so I explained again that I refused to involve my mother in setting up my financial accounts, thanked her for her time again, and left.

At this point, I was exhausted. I had been walking all day. I mulled over the parental note idea a bit, but reached two conclusions. First, if any telephone number is needed, be that mine or my mother's, I've chosen the wrong financial institution. The telephone number system is a pile of rubbish, and I will not buy into it needlessly. If this parental note requires my mother's telephone number to be valid, it is not a viable option for me. Second, what happens if I *do* bring back a parental note? It's quite obvious that such a note is not really good for anything. I would be wasting a third trip to the credit union with almost certainly nothing to show for it. There's no point in this. Utterly defeated, I decided to try a bank. The problem with banks is that they don't care about their customers. They just want to make money. That said, it's also their strength in this case. A bank doesn't have idiotic membership requirements usually. If the bank would not accept the credit card statement as proof of my current address, they almost certainly would accept the address on my state-issued ID, not caring that I supposedly live far from the place I plan to do my banking. If I was going to break down and choose a bank instead of a credit union, there were two obvious choices. Bank of America and Banner Bank are both a lot closer to my house than any credit union. Days ago, I went into both of these institutions trying to get them to make change for me. Bank of America refused on the grounds that I didn't have an account with them, and despite my explaining that I had issues with Bank of America last time I had an account with them, they tried to get me to register a new account without addressing my concerns. In fact, they just brushed off my concerns as if they were nothing. Banner Bank on the other hand, made change for me without hassle. Aside from this single interaction with them, I have no experience with them whatsoever. So I chose Banner Bank.

Hoping that this would be the last stop before we headed home, I stopped in Banner Bank. The representative that helped me asked why I had chosen Banner Bank, so I explained how my day had gone very briefly. She assured me that Banner Bank would cause me no such hassles. Everything seemed to be going fine, but then she got to the dreaded question: What is your telephone number? I explained that I haven't had telephone service in about six months. She said that the only thing the telephone number is needed for is the debit card, and that if there were any questionable purchases with it, they would need to reach me by telephone. If I had no number, the bank would be forced to shut off the card in such a situation, as they would be unable to reach me. I explained that I don't spend from a debit card; that I pay in cash-only except when online, where I use my credit card. Likewise, I explained that I like my privacy, so my credit card doesn't even have my legal name. As she had told me that the debit card issued by the bank she represented would be required to have my legal name on it, I explained that I couldn't even use my Banner Bank debit card for online purchases. I said that if it would be easier for her, she didn't need to issue the debit card at all, as I wouldn't be able to make use of it anyway. This didn't seem to satisfy her, but at the same time, she didn't want to turn me away. I don't know if my tired look and story of my frustrating day played into this, but she wanted to do what she could to make this work, and didn't want me to go without a debit card, saying that the debit card could be used to retrieve cash from any ATM, even if I prefer to pay for merchandise using cash. After talking to her boss, she got the account set up, saying that my debit card would come in the mail. Unfortunately, the checking accounts at banner bank gain no interest. The saving accounts gain very little interest, and come with the stipulation that they cost money to maintain unless $25 USD is automatically transfered from checking to savings each month. The counter-productive part of this is that it means that a customer cannot put all their money into savings, though the point seems to be to get people to put money into savings.

At some point during the process, we had discussed the fact that United States telephone numbers in the format XXX-555-01XX are dead numbers, so she may have used one of those numbers to set up the account. She, like many people, had thought that *all* numbers in the XXX-555-XXXX range are dead numbers, but this hasn't been the case for a while. Most of these numbers have become assignable now, and I think it's because we're running out of available telephone numbers. This is just one more reason we need to move away from the telephone number system to something more flexible, such as SIP addressing.

Today Oregon First Community Credit Union decided to be unreasonable, and they lost a customer. Banner Bank decided to be reasonable, and gained one. I've lost faith in banks, and would have much preferred a credit union, but the fact is, I need a place to deposit paychecks and avoid paycheck-cashing fees. If things go wrong at Banner Bank, there is an unfortunate likelihood that I will go back to Oregon First Community Credit Union despite the hassles they caused. By then, I will probably have the letter containing the ID-amending sticker from the DMV and the letter containing the debit card from Banner Bank, both ow which might work as proof of residency. But for now, as long as Banner Bank wants to play nicely, there is a very strong chance I will stay with Banner Bank for a long while, potentially as long as I remain here in Coos Bay.

I do not have Internet service at my home and cannot update my warrant canary.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

An email address for my resume

Day 00186: Wednesday, 2015 September 09

The main thing on today's agenda was to set up an email account for me to use when hunting for jobs. I definitely want to be reachable by email, but if I use my main email account, it may lead potential employers back to my website due to using my own domain as the host name. I don't need employers knowing about my journal here and judging my by it until *after* they hire me. I don't care if they fire me for my weblog later, though I doubt that would happen.

I tried to use Toco Bell's Wi-Fi today, but it just wasn't working. I wasn't sure why at the time, but I would find that out later in the day. With that option ruled out, I headed to the far side of North Bend, to the public library.

At the library, I found that Wi-Fi service there was not working either. I asked the librarian about it, but he said that the technical person was out for the day. After some fiddling around with settings, I found that the library Wi-Fi is a captive portal. I whitelisted the library router's IP address so it would bypass the Tor proxy, but that didn't help. I read and agreed to the terms of service, but unless I fully disabled my proxy, I couldn't do much. While the library is awesome for using Linux on their computers, they also seem to block some of their ports. Clearnet web goes through (I tested by checking Wikipedia, feeling Wikipedia was probably safe to visit without a proxy for now), but both the ping port and the Tor port are blocked even if you agree to the router's terms of service. The librarian asked me to write a note to the technical guy, which the librarian would submit as a support ticket. I may check back on this later.

With captive portals in mind, I headed back to Taco Bell. I found their router's IP address and whitelisted that as well. Once I had agreed to the terms of service, all ports (or at least the ping and Tor ports, which I use) opened up and I was able to use the Internet as usual. Unlike the library, Taco Bell is closer to my home, but also unlike the library, Taco Bell has no electrical outlets for me to use. I'll have to use batter power when I'm online, making my Internet sessions limited in length.

Searching for a primary email address provider these days is difficult if you don't want to give out personal information. Most gratis email providers require you to give them your telephone number, a trend I'm almost certain Google set. As I am against the telephone number system and do not use telephone service, I couldn't supply these websites with my telephone number even if I *did* want to. I simply do not have a telephone number. Other providers insist that you give them your current email address before they will let you register. What if this was my first email account? There must be a way to set up an initial email account for people who do not yet have an email account and do not have telephone service. Besides, I don't want my new email account associated with my main email account. If I wasn't trying to create this separation, I could just use an address at my own domain. Finally, some email account providers want money. But if handing over my current email address is too personal, I think handing over my credit card information is also too personal. Not to mention that I don't plan to use this account much, I just want a small account to use for job hunting and nothing else.

Finally, after much searching, I found VFEmail. They have paid options, which I may look into later (they allow receiving email to your own domain as part of their paid packages), but they also have a gratis account option. They had several domain options for gratis accounts, using TLDs that non-tech-savvy people (such as some potential employers) will recognize. I decided to use the "clovermail.net" domain, as it seems benign, is pronounceable, and uses the recognized //net. TLD.

With that out of the way, I spent what limited time I had left searching for ISPs in the area. The one that kept popping up was Charter. Some websites either claimed that it was the only option in the area, or just said that Charter is the provider for this area. I will come back and do more research tomorrow.

I do not have Internet service at my home and cannot update my warrant canary.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Cable monopolies

Day 00187: Thursday, 2015 September 10

I went down to Taco Bell again to use their Wi-Fi to research ISPs again. I've tried searching on my mobile, but the tiny screen makes it difficult and many websites discriminate against mobile devices, refusing to show them the full available content and information. One of the first sites I found held bad news: Because of government licensing, cable companies don't typically overlap in the same area. I think this is a lie, at least in part. There probably is only one cable provider in most areas, but I doubt it is due to government licensing. I hear that Comcast and Time Warner specifically avoid setting foot on each other's turf as part of an agreement between the two to preserve their own respective monopolies. I wouldn't be surprised if most of the other cable companies have that sort of agreement going as well. This means that we either have to choose Charter, or we have to choose a slower DSL provider.

I looked into their pricing, but it isn't all clear. All prices are given as being for the first year. Nowhere on the website does it mention what the price will rise to later. I spoke with a representative via Web chat that told me that the bill would rise $10 to $15 USD per month after the initial year. Looking at their prices, they try to get you to bundle your services by offering discounts to do so. Internet service alone costs $40 ($39.99) USD per month. My mother will probably also want television service, which together with Internet service, will cost a whopping $90 ($89.98) USD per month. Throwing telephone service on top of that brings the bill to $90 ($89.97) USD per month, one cent less than the bill would be without telephone service. If they're going to charge less with the telephone service added in, we might as well get that. Having a telephone at which to receive calls for interviews might mean the difference between getting a job and not. Plus, because it's a land line and not a line that follows me around, I can completely ignore all calls once I actually have a job, or at the very least, I can be unaware of calls until I get home with a reasonable excuse. I can tell my employer that while email reaches me right away wherever I am, telephone calls won't reach me until I get home. Premium channels are available for either $20 or $40 USD more, but I doubt my mother will want those and I'm not interested even in the basic television service. When she gets back, I'll discuss the options with her, then I will probably place the order for service using the Taco Bell Wi-Fi tomorrow.

*UPDATE*: I spoke with my mother, and it seems that she didn't want my to order the service anyway. I was under the impression that she wanted this to be a bill I covered, but it seems that isn't the case. She wanted the bill to be under my name only if we had Comcast service as part of some money-saving scheme that doesn't apply to Charter service. The worst part is that she wanted me to hand my Social Security number over to Comcast. If I were to sign up for Comcast service, I certainly wouldn't give them my Social Security number. She asked me to try to set up the service, but said that she would cover the bill. I said I'd get my stuff together and head down to Taco Bell to use their Internet connection to set up our own, but she didn't like that idea. She asked if I had tried calling Charter by telephone, so I reminded her that I don't have telephone service. What I didn't mention is that I'd be willing to walk over thirty kilometers to find an Internet connection and order that way just to avoid making a single telephone call. I hate dealing with people (and machines) over the telephone. She ended up placing the order herself. While I much prefer Web forms and Web chats, she seems to usually prefer doing things over the telephone. She ordered Internet, television, and telephone service, though the bill was higher than I expected. They require the rental of cable boxes anywhere we want television, so she had rented two cable boxes, one for her bedroom and one for family use. The bill came to $104 ($103.95) USD per month. Charter requires that we have one of their employees come in to set things up, they won't allow us to set them up ourselves. This person will come by on Tuesday, supposedly somewhere from 08:00 to 10:00, and the installation is supposed to take one to three hours. We'll see if they actually show up on time though. I guess I'll wait until then to start looking for work so I will have a telephone number to put on job applications. I won't put the telephone number anywhere that doesn't specifically request one though, so my resume will not have it and any place that requests resumes will not have the telephone number.

I'm likely headed back to Springfield this weekend, so with Internet service here almost up, I'll bring my server back with me. This will of course cause more down time likely than if I waited until service was set up here, but I honestly don't know when the next chance I'll have to visit Springfield will be. For that matter, I don't know when the Internet connection in Springfield will be cut off. Having the server back here will put my mind at ease more.

I feel like everything I can accomplish for the time being is already complete. Tomorrow, I'll head down to Taco Bell again to update my warrant canary and my weblog.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Goodbye world!

Day 00188: Friday, 2015 September 11

I walked into Subway this morning to see if they had anything edible. I already knew that their veggie patties contained dairy, but I wasn't sure about their bread. I asked, and it turns out that all of their bread contains dairy, at least according to the servers on duty (they didn't check, they were going from memory). However, it turns out that Subway offers salads that are essentially just sandwich toppings that have been cut up and put in a bowl. They first add whatever toppings you want to a large plastic bowl, then use a hand-held bladed tool to chop it all up. The result was quite delicious, and if you leave out the meat, it's actually a bit less expensive than if you add meat.

I decided that it would be a good idea to check in with AT&T before discontinuing my Cricket plan. I needed to make sure that they are a carrier that allows tablet plans to be used with non-tablet devices. According to the representatives, they cannot do this. The reason they gave is that the tablet SIM cards and plans actually do allow calling if the device supports it, so if the device supports it, they have to charge for it by putting the device on a smartphone plan instead. In other words, their system is not set up to deliver only what they charge you for, so instead of fixing their system, they have decided to charge you for calling features even if you never plan to use them. It looks like I'm sticking with Cricket for the time being. Their plans are cheaper than the AT&T plans that have calling features and at least one gigabyte of data. Cricket also offers unlimited data usage, it's just throttled after two point five gigabytes of usage. I'll probably never use that much data in a month anyway.

I tried to update my website today, but I found once again that onion addresses do not play well with specified ports. For example, if I was trying to reach sftp://abcdefghijklmnop.onion/, it would work fine. But if I try reaching sftp://abcdefghijklmnop.onion:1234/, the onion address will not resolve. It won't matter too much longer anyway though. I've looked into it, and Charter does not allow customers to run home servers. I'm going to have to take down my website. I can't even guarantee that this weblog entry will be available for reading before the website has to come down. Losing my Web server means not only losing this website, but also losing my ownCloud instance and minet.y.st. It's a shame, but I don't know what I can do about it.

There's a video game store at the local mall here. Obviously the games aren't worth looking into because they are all proprietary, but it turns out that they double as a Cricket dealer. I saw the sign on their door, so I stopped in and asked them about it. I specifically asked if that meant I could pay my bill in-person there, and I was told that I could. I shouldn't have any more credit card rejection issues from them if I pay in-person and in cash, not to mention the fact that I prefer using cash anyway.

When I got home, I found that an envelope from Banner Bank had arrived in the mail. I thought of course that this was my debit card that had finally arrived, but this was not the case. Instead, it was a hand-written thank you card from the representative who had set up my account along with a copy of her business card. This was the same business card that she had sent with me in the folder full of terms of service and other documents the day the account was created. Why are the Banner Bank representatives sending thank you cards for setting up accounts? It's not offensive or anything, but it's a little strange. And I get the feeling that this isn't an isolated incident. Both the thank you card and its envelope have the bank logo printed on them, so they are likely mass-produced.

The debit card was not in the envelope, so unless it was sent separately, it's not coming. That's fine though, as I had told the bank representative, I have no plans to use it. I simply am waiting for it because I think that it is coming. Although, as I write this paragraph, it occurs to me that the debit card is likely not being sent by the bank representative, while this hand-written note appears to have come from her. There is therefore a high probability that the two were sent separately, so the card is probably still on its way, not that that actually matters or anything.

I feel worn down. I feel defeated. This place sucks.

I think a big part of my exhaustion is emotional. My website is a big part of what I enjoy in life, and now it's being taken away from me. I've also had to migrate from a mostly-non-evil mobile network to a very evil one in order to remain in service. I have no Internet access at home, which is quite stressful. My mother has been trying to get me to learn to drive so I can drive her fossil fuel-burning van for her. But also, I have to walk down a hill from my new home to get anywhere of consequence, then walk back up the hill to get back home. I've been doing this almost every day for a while now. I'm physically exhausted too from this. I'll try to keep a positive attitude, or at least I'll pretend to, but I can't wait to get out of here. Maybe things will mellow out a bit and life will be good again, even here, but for now, I'm not happy here.

I may try to get some sort of place holder up where my site was for now. Between the fact that I stamp money with my Web address and the fact that I'm paying Josh Woodward to link back to my website at $10 USD per link, I really shouldn't allow too much down time. Even if I can only get a single page up at my domain, I need to do it. That page can act as a hub to the rest of my online identity, even if it does nothing else. Even if it has nothing else, a prospective host for my temporary site while I'm here must have HTTPS support and an option to use my own domain name. It's of no use if https://y.st/ doesn't lead to a working version of the website.

I was going to bring over my Web server this weekend, but perhaps that is a bad idea now. I should leave it where it is until the Internet connection there is cut off. If this page is seen, let it serve as my goodbye. This could be the end of Yst Domain for the time being.

My canary may be offline indefinitely.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Vaccinated

Day 00189: Saturday, 2015 September 12

It turns out that we didn't head to Springfield today as planned, though we did hit the other two places that we had planned to go.

First, we went to an emergency preparedness fair. I was disappointed that there weren't any lectures or seminars on emergency preparedness there, only a bunch of booths, but it turns out this is only because my mother wanted to leave early. Had we stayed, there would have been lectures. We did get gratis vaccinations against tetanus, diphtheria, and pertussis though, which may save us some suffering later.

Next, we went to the cranberry festival. Oddly enough, there was hardly anything there that had any relation to cranberries. One boot that did actually fit the theme of the fair explained how cranberries are farmed. It turns out that cranberries aren't grown underwater like I thought they were. The supposed "bogs" that they are grown in are actually dryish. The plants grow on ground that is not submerged in the water, but when it comes time to harvest them, the farmers flood the bog, then drive a machine over it to agitate the plants and knock the berries off. They do this because the berries float, to then it's a simple matter of taking a floating barrier across the top of the water to scoop up the berries. Then they are free to drain the bog again in preparation for the next growing season.

Before going to bed, I set up my mother's computer for her. She got it a while ago, but hadn't set it up yet and didn't know how. Part of the problem was that she was missing three cords, had no mouse, and had a keyboard that was way too old for her machine. I pulled the missing components out of my spare part stash, including a replacement keyboard, and got everything working. Unfortunately, the machine is running Windows 8. Debian 8 would be a much better choice, but she refuses to try anything besides Windows. Oh well, I'm not the one that will have to deal with losing my data when the operating system inevitably fails. Nor will I be the one constantly having to try to bend the thing to my will. If she wants to deal with the hassles, that's her choice.

My ID update label from the DMV arrived today. I have no intention of actually applying it to my ID though. After all, there's no reason to, really. Who am I trying to prove my address to, anyway? I've already gotten an account set up at a bank. I can't think of anyone besides a credit union that needs proof of my legal identity's address. Anyone else can either believe my when I tell them my address or not believe me, I don't really care.

With my website going down soon, and this entry potentially not being uploaded before that happens, this may be the last time I mention my canary for a while.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

It's been a long day, but somehow, I think tomorrow will be longer

Day 00190: Sunday, 2015 September 13

This morning, my mother gave me what she thought was a driver's manual, though I don't know why she thought that was what it was. It was clearly titled "The Oregon Guide to Teen Driving". I can't even consider reading the thing anyway, due to it being released under the CC BY-NC-SA license, a license that prohibits commercialism, and is therefor nonfree. I'm not even sure why it's under any license at all. Supposedly, it was published by the Oregon Department of Transportation, a part of the government, and should therefore fall outside of copyright. It should be in the public domain, not under any license at all. In any case, the actual driver's manual has no such mention of any licensing, and is probably in the public domain as it should be.

For part of the day, I worked at my mother's school to help her with her classroom, but we quickly rushed off because she wanted to go find yard sales. I found a telephone for only one dollar, but I had lost my money pouch. I would later find it at home, but it was too late by then. We went to the local second hand shop, where I picked up an answering machine for two dollars, but I'm still missing the main telephone component to this setup. I'm not sure what to do, I'm running out of time before Tuesday, when we might have service. After that, we went back to the school for more classroom preparations.

When we got back home, my mother found an advertisement for cheaper Internet access. She asked me to call them up to inquire, and I had to remind her that I do not have an active telephone line. She got frustrated, but the truth is, with or without a telephone line, I will do whatever it takes to get out of making a telephone call. Telephone conversations simply irk me to no end. Also, truth be told, I actually do have a line of service through Cricket at the moment, but only because they do not offer tablet plans and because AT&T refuses to allow a tablet plan to be used with a smartphone. I do not want to be reachable by telephone wherever I go, and I have all but completely disabled the telephone functionality of my device. I'd finish disabling it, but doing so seems to also disable the data connection.

I looked up Frontier, the company my mother found, on the Web. Unfortunately, while they do have a Web presence, they do not list their prices online. I'm going to have to spend my day tomorrow walking to see them in person just to ask about prices that I should be able to see on their website. I've got better things to do than this. I am going to go in, and when they ask how I'm doing as most businesses do, I'll tell them that I'm not happy and explain the situation. There is no excuse for hiding their prices by omitting them from the website.

Yesterday, I ended up with three tsunami evacuation maps, two of which I will stash away until I need them. The third, I've marked my house on and will use for navigation. My street is not labeled on the map, but both streets one block away have been labeled, so once I checked what streets I am between, it wasn't too hard to find my street. The street Frontier is on is labeled, so it won't bee to hard to find my way there. Still, I have to navigate my way around an unlabeled lake, and I'm not sure which direction is more efficient.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Wasting paper

Day 00191: Monday, 2015 September 14

I made it to Frontier, but when I went in, I wasn't able to make myself come off as angry as I wanted to. I had rehearsed in my head what to say, but that's not what came out of my mouth. It turns out this was a good thing though. I explained my frustration with the website not showing the service prices, and the representative pulled up the website on his monitor. The prices were right there in plain sight and even in large print. Thinking that the website might be discriminating against mobile devices as some websites do, I tried pulling up the website from my mobile. When the page finally loaded, the prices were right there, plain as day. I forgot to ask if Frontier allows customers to run their own Web servers, but it doesn't really matter much. If we were getting only Internet service, Frontier would have been the cheaper option. However, my mother really likes having television service, and with television service taken into account, Charter is the cheaper service.

However, that trip was not wasted. On the way home, I located a couple of the large discount food stores in the area, knowledge of which will prove useful in keeping vegan food available around the house.

As I neared home, I took a detour to stop by the bank and the game store that doubles as a Cricket retailer. At the bank, I deposited all my coins into my account and withdrew my usual $100 USD in one dollar bills. To my mild dismay, I had to sign two small paper slips, one for the deposit and one for the withdrawal. The problem wasn't the signing though, it was the wasted paper. Why wasn't this done digitally? What are they even going to do with the papers I signed? And this is going to happen every time I stop by for a transaction.

At the game store, I found that Cricket transactions are not possible when dealing with every game store representative. Some representatives can access the Cricket system, but others are not authorized. The representative present at the time was not one of the ones that could access the Cricket system, and said that if I came back after 13:00, the representative I needed to talk to would be in. I asked if there was any sort of pattern to when these people would be in so I would know when I could pay my bill and not, and she said that in general, they always show up at about 13:00, so today was not unique in that regard. I was about two hours too early, so I headed home for food, rest, and a shower, then headed back and paid my bill.

When I got back home for the second time today, I found that I had received two letters from Banner Bank. Surely one of the two held my debit card, right? Nope. Flexing the envelopes, I found that there was no card in either. I opened the first and found that it had my bank statement for my checking account, but not my savings account. It seems a bit soon to be receiving a statement, but whatever. I opened the second envelope expecting to see that the bank had been wasting paper again, and that they had put my savings account information on a separate statement, but that was no the case at all. Instead, the second envelope contained a second copy of the exact same checking account statement! Why is Banner Bank sending me two of the same statement? These people really like to waste paper. Once Internet access is set up here, perhaps I'll be able to log in somewhere and get my statements switched over to e-statements. That should save at least some paper.

My sister is coming over for another visit and to pick up the mail key, and our mother has asked that she bring over the router this time. With the router gone from our former residence, my server will now be disconnected from the Internet, so the site is now going down. With no reason left to leave the server there, I've asked that she bring that over here as well. She also said she is bringing my bicycle, so once I have that, I'll take the chain off of it and go buy that chainless bicycle at the pawn shop, assuming it is still there.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

We have Internet access again!

Day 00192: Tuesday, 2015 September 15

I was looking through my music today to decide what to put on, and I found that I only had one version of Golden Sunrise. The main version was still in my collection, but I had managed to delete the alternate version that you get for signing up for Josh Woodward's mailing list. My guess is that I deleted it when I bought his $40 USD music pack. I've re-added myself to the mailing list (with the same address as before), then re-downloaded the song.

The Charter cable guy came over to install our new equipment from them. He actually arrived within about ten minutes of the start of our appointment window, so I didn't have to wait long. My mother was at work, so I showed him where we wanted our new equipment. He kept cutting cables that did not need to be cut because they could have just been screwed off. Then, he would strip the ends and add a new screw-on attachment piece so he could connect new pieces that replaced the ones he could have just screwed off. He used a wrench to tighten them, so he did have a wrench on hand. He wasn't cutting the wires because he didn't have the tools needed to remove pieces the right way! He also mentioned the way satellite dish-based service providers do things. When they come to set up your service, they don't care if you already have one of your dishes on your roof; they'll install a new one either way. They also don't take the dishes down when you leave because it's gratis advertisement. The house we are renting has three on the roof; the one across the street has four.

When he was setting up the modem, we couldn't find any cable outlets along the wall in the room where my mother wanted the modem to be. The cable guy ended up installing a splitter in the room across the hall, then running a long cable along the wall to the corner of the room closest to the room we wanted it in. The theory was that once the wireless router was installed there, it would give signal closest to where we wanted it, and we could install a wireless card to the computer that would have had a direct connection if the room had been wired for cable. When my mother got home, she was not happy. It turns out that there had been a cable outlet in that room, it had just been set in the floor instead of in the wall where it should have been and where we looked for it. I tried moving the modem to the proper cable outlet, but it fails to function there. The automated chat robot said we could move it anywhere that we had a cable outlet, that it wasn't bound to a single place. I spoke with a Charter representative online, and she said that the cable company only activated the modem to work on a single outlet. We can't move it. I asked the representative what we needed to do to get the other outlet activated. SHe said we would need to pay a $50 USD fee and have another cable guy come over and set it up. I offered to pay for the mistake myself, but my mother was not happy about this solution, and we are now working around the problem as it is.

I tried to set up the machine that used to be my server, but it seems I had not brought my jar of miscellaneous small computer parts as I thought I had. In that jar is a critical piece: an adapter that allows the monitor to speak with the machine. The jar must still be at my former residence, so I will have to set this up later.

I tried to find a gratis Web host that I could just put up a single-page HTTPS website at until I get back to an areas and ISP that will allow me to run my own Web server again, but I had no such luck today. One host looks like what I need, but they don't recognize //st. domains as valid. I found a website called Wix, but they don't seem to allow you to code your paged yourself, so you have to use their painful graphical editor. If I get desperate, I may end up using Wix.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

After only one day of service, we now know the cable company lies

Day 00193: Wednesday, 2015 September 16

I spent today making another run to Springfield to grab some of the family's belongings, this time with my sister. Our goal was to grab one or two specific filing cabinets from our former residence, along with whatever else we could pack into the remaining space of the van. We managed to get both filing cabinets through a little ingenuity, then filled the rest of the space mostly with clothing. We also stopped by a second-hand store and picked up a telephone for my job hunt and a Wi-Fi card for our mother's computer. I forgot to grab a telephone cord from the second-hand store or from our former residence, but luckily, the cable company left us a telephone cord when they set up our service. I also grabbed my small jar of miscellaneous tiny computer parts, which contains the adapter I I need to plug a monitor into my former server.

We checked for mail, and found that CREDO Mobile sent me a letter inviting me to purchase an iPhone from them along with a two-year contract. They have sent me this same invitation by email countless times, but it seems they've given up and resorted to paper mail to try to get my attention that way. The iPhone, service contracts, and CDMA all suck. I'm not buying an iPhone and I'm not choosing CREDO as my carrier.

When we got home, we found that another cable guy came over to check our satisfaction with the first cable guy's work. My mother explained the issue with the modem placement, and the cable guy told her that the outlet that she wanted to use for the modem didn't actually connect to the cable company's system at all. Rather, it was connected to one of the two satelite dishes on the roof. He also told my mother that I had not allowed the first cable guy to enter the attic, which wasn't true at all. The first cable guy didn't even express any interest in the attic, and if he had, I would have lead him there without hesitation. We're new in this house, and the attic is still completely empty. We have nothing in there to hide. My mother figured this was the case, but asked me about it anyway just to see if she was wrong. It looks like my mistake yesterday didn't cost us too much though, as we wouldn't have been able to use the cable outlet that she wanted to use anyway.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The website might be coming back up

Day 00194: Thursday, 2015 September 17

I found another website that claims to redirect traffic from your domain to any website of your choosing, but it claims my email address is invalid. The website also offers gratis email accounts (where was this website when I needed it?), but after registering an email account, the new email address was also rejected as invalid. If the website is claiming that even email addresses on their own servers at their own domain are invalid, it's probably going to claim all email addresses are invalid.

Next, I tried crawling back to Namecheap. I left them because they started serving Tor users Cloudflare CAPTCHA pages, but their gratis DNS service also provides HTTP (and maybe HTTPS) redirects. I begrudgingly filled out the CAPTCHA, but when I went to register an account, Namecheap refused to allow me to set up an account on the grounds that I am using an anonymous proxy. I was willing to meet them half-way by filling out the CAPTCHA that they serve only to proxy users, but I refuse to let down my proxy to deal with these people. Requiring someone to reach you without an anonymous proxy is a direct attack on security, anonymity, and privacy.

Next, I registered an account at freedns.ws. They claim to have "domain name redirection", which I was hoping meant HTTP redirection. However, when I tried to add records for my domain, I found that their system had no support for the //st. TLD. They blocked the records, claiming that they were incomplete unless I added a ".com" to the end of the domain name, which would obviously specified the wrong domain.

Though it has disadvantages, I set up an account at afraid.org. They provide HTTP redirects, but they do not provide redirects over HTTPS and they allow other people to register a subdomain under your domain. It's a price I'm willing to pay for the time being though. If they offered redirects over HTTPS, I would probably use the paid version though to prevent random usage of my subdomains.

Lastly, I tried to set up a Wordpress weblog. They allow use of your own domain (I think even complete with HTTPS), for a fee. However, Wordpress.com claims that the y.st domain is not currently registered, which is untrue. Wordpress.com must just not be compatible with domains under the //st. TLD.

Lastly for the day, I updated my Credit Union accounts from Springfield to use my new postal address. The First Tech Federal Credit Union was slow as usual, and it was difficult to find the log in page (I had to do a Web search for it, it doesn't seem to be accessible from the home page), but once logged in, everything went smoothly. The Oregon Community Credit Union website on the other hand kept giving me trouble. In some places, it was refusing to accept my password, then locking up my account for twenty minutes at a time due to an "incorrect password". After much frustration, I found that while the Oregon Community Credit Union website puts a thirty-two character cap on password length, one part of the website uses a different cap. If your password is over thirty characters, it is not accepted on that one page.

I received notice that I owe Josh Woodward another ten dollars for music, as he has just put out a new post on Patreon. This time, instead of paying $10 USD for a single song, it seems I'm paying only $10 USD for a set of thirty short preludes. But here's the catch: these songs are proprietary! They are under the CC BY-NC license, meaning that I am funding evilly-licensed music that I don't even get to listen to. I am very disappointed with Woodward on this one. If he wants to release his music as proprietary, that's bad enough, but to charge his Patreon supporters for it is a new level of bad. I'll bite my tongue on this one though.

At the end of the day, wowaname offered to set up a place for my website on her server, complete with HTTPS. If she does that, I can keep links I've paid Josh Woodward for from breaking, as well as keep the URI I stamp on dollar bills valid. If this doesn't work out though, I might just give up. I'm under too much stress as it is, and I don't need to keep the search for a Web host in my burden. As usual, being paranoid, I dread the worst outcome even when it appears the solution to my problem is just around the corner.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Yst Domain Light

Day 00195: Friday, 2015 September 18

I have now resigned to downloading the audio and textual driver's manual from the official Oregon website. If my understanding is correct, anything produced by a government employee on behalf of the government falls outside copyright and into the public domain, so these files should be safe. I'm really going to hate being a driver, but it should get my mother off my case. I can run her errands for her, lightening her load. Although, the fact is that she knows that I'm already willing to run any in-city errands for her, I just do it on foot, which she does not like. Having a driver's license won't change that, and I will continue to run any feasible errands without a car. The only difference is that I will have having a driver's license weighing down on my conscious.

I walked to the store to get DVDs to back up my mother's Windows operating system as she wanted. However, when I got home, I found that she had run a system update, which sort of defeats the purpose of the initial backup. She had wanted to be able to revert any changes made later, in case something went wrong. Not only did updating the system prematurely mean that we now can't revert that change, but it also means that backing the system up will cost two extra DVDs! Or rather, it would have cost two extra DVDs, if backing the system up was possible at all. It seems that the system backup in Windows has been broken since Windows Vista. If my mother is going to run Windows, a screwy system, she's going to keep running into issues such as this.

My new Mobile case arrived in the mail today, which means that Yst Dawson now has proof of address! I probably won't need this for quite a while, but it's nice to have it on hand, just in case I need it. As for the case itself, it snapps together very tightly, and does not seem to be made for constant removal the way my last case was. It's also a lot thinner, so I worry if it is as protective as the last one. However, the buttons are much more usable that when my mobile was in that last case, so perhaps it's a trade-off. Hopefully this case will at least be enough.

Wowaname set up an account on her system for me today so I could get my website uploaded! Being paranoid, I thought there would be a high probability that it would slip her mind to do so, but I had nothing to worry about after all. She asked if I would rather connect to the sever via SSH over Tor or the clearnet, so I said that I connect to everything over Tor. It turns out that this worked well for her, as she already has an onion address set up for reaching her ssh server over Tor, but it sounded like working over the clearnet would require extra setup. I hadn't even factored onions into the equation though. On my own server, I just use Thunar and GVFS to access remote storage over SFTP, but I don't know how to proxy my connection with that setup. Even if I wanted to drop the proxy, I can't reach onion addresses without it.

I decided to give in and work over basic SSH on the command line, but it seems that either the server or my account is configured to only allow SFTP connections. I tried to look up a method of proxying a connection from such a setup, but I got nowhere. I ended up installing Filezilla, which has the basic proxy settings I need. All that's really needed to run through Tor is SOCKS5 compatibility, I just don't know how to set that up with my usual applications.

I generated a new certificate (as my old one is too personal and doubles as my client certificate), and wowaname set that up as well. She offered to host an onion version of my website as well if I uploaded the key to it, but I saw little point to that. If the onion points to the same site, the main address does not block Tor, and the main address is over HTTPS, there really isn't much point in it. Besides, if I change my mind, I think the onion can run on my end, as onions function not as servers, but as clients.

A new version of my website, which I am now dubbing "Yst Domain Light", is now live. I didn't want to upload the full website to wowaname's server, as I don't want to be too much of a burden. This new website holds only a single page that lists where I can be found around the Internet and thanks wowaname for her help by hosting this.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

American Samoa's ccTLD

Day 00198: Monday, 2015 September 21

I wrote to Hover asking about how to register a domain name given the fact that I do not have a telephone number, but have yet to receive a response. I anticipate that they will respond, but be unable to help with the situation. I've decided that the best course of action is to check out ccTLDs instead. The ccTLD registries don't have to play by all the same rules as the gTLDs, and sometimes this leads to friendlier registration requirements. I've revived the old ccTLD list I once used to hunt down a short domain name and will add information about which ccTLDs allow registration without a telephone number.

Originally, this list was lost when my hard drive died on my in February. However, mistedwind found a copy of it in Google's virtual garbage can before they had a chance to empty it, and insisted that I keep it available, be it on the main website or on the satellite onion website that I control. Until now, I shunned that page, as it was part of an incomplete set. The old website was lost, so it could not go there, but it had no context in the new website, so it didn't really belong here. I think new information gives the list some context within this website though, so it now makes some sense to quit treating it as rubbish from another lifetime.

I actually had to rescue the ccTLD information from my former server, which proved more difficult than I was hoping. The problem is that it has no GUI, so mounting a USB drive would have been more of a challenge than I was up to today, but the machine also has no Wi-Fi capabilities, so I couldn't just use SFTP from my laptop. I tried installing my old Wi-Fi adapter from my Frankenbuild, but that Wi-Fi card is missing it's antenna and I couldn't find it. I then installed the Wi-Fi card meant for my mother's computer, only to realize that without a GUI, trying to get it to know which network to connect to was going to be a pain. I ended up dragging the machine downstairs and plugging it directly into the router, as had been the setup back in Springfield. I had to take it all apart for the night when I was done, but I retrieved the file I wanted.

A certain someone that does not like to be mentioned by name asked where my weblog can be found, so I explained that my weblog is not publicly-available at the moment, due to my website being majorly stripped-down. I further explained that the reason for the website being stripped down was to avoid being a burden to wowaname and her server. Wowaname piped up and said that she was fine with me uploading my full website, so I explained that I don't have a reasonable way to update it yet. Every time I update my website, I literally delete the whole thing off the server and reupload it, which can't be very good for the server's hard drive or bandwidth. Wowaname suggested using rsync, which seems like an easy enough tool to use and might work over SFTP. I'll have to try it tomorrow.

My debit card from the bank arrived, but by the time I knew it was here, the bank was already closed. I'll walk into the bank tomorrow to get it activated. I suspect that they will tell me that I either could activate it via telephone or that I *must* activate it via telephone. If the latter, I'll ask to use one of the bank's own telephones. I need to remember to bring in my Social Security card, just in case the number off of it is needed for card activation. The funny part is that I don't even plan to use this card. The representative that set up my account insisted that I get one though, so now that I have it, I want to know how friendly the bank's system is to people without telephones.

After checking up on the first several ccTLD registries today, I found one that appears to allow registration without a telephone number! The //as. registry asks for a telephone number and a fax number, but the telephone number can be set to any arbitrary string (such as "no telephone number available") and the fax number can be left blank.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Austria, Bosnia, and Herzegovina

Day 00200: Wednesday, 2015 September 23

I found a couple registries that seem to be friendly to people without telephones. The first is the registry run by the Republic of Austria. This registry does some strange math as far as prices are concerned, but their registration form's telephone number field is marked as optional. They also allow you to keep some of your information out of the whois database, even if it is required information or information that you chose to give. Your name and postal address are still required to be in the database, but I'm not too concerned about that. They also offer to send you your invoice by paper mail if you want, though if you opt for an email invoice instead, you get a discount. Paper invoices seem like a waste of paper and a waste of time. Email statements can be automated better and arrive sooner, but I guess in some businesses, having it sent by postal mail might fill some red tape obligation.

The second registry is run by Bosnia and Herzegovina. Their website is only available in Bosnian, and their registration form's telephone field is required to be filled. However, this field takes strings as well as numbers, so "no telephone number available" can be used in place of a telephone number.

Wowaname said she might be able to clean up the ugly script I use to compile this website, but it turned out my script was too ugly to make much sense of. She tried to enable the script to detect when the source code has been changed so it would recompile all of the pages that need to be recompiled without recompiling any of the pages that don't need to be recompiled. She tried having the script compare the uncompiled page to the copy that had been compiled last time the compile script had been run, but that didn't work because the compiled code will always be different from the uncompiled code. I explained to her that the only two ways I could think of to have the compile script auto-detect which files needed to be recompiled was either saving a copy of each uncompiled page at compile time to use for comparison next time or have the compiler compile every page every time, then check the newly-compiled version of the page against the old compiled version, and only write to disk if the two did not match. Both of these would be suboptimal, but especially the latter because it means compiling everything every time. Wowaname insists that I need to add this recompile-everything functionality to my script though. I feel like I'm in a tight position because I can't really say "no", but at the same time, I really don't like the thought of compiling everything every time. I added the check for already-compiled pages (though this check can't check the code for modification) because rebuilding the whole website was getting slower and slower each time a new page was added. My new machine can handle rebuilding the whole website loads better than my old one could, but the site will continue to grow and will hit the limits of this machine as well. What happens in ten years when I have over ten years worth of weblog entries that will all be getting compiled daily? And what happens if I go back to a weaker machine?

I explained my fears to wowaname, and her suggestion was to treat the weblog section of the website differently. Most of the website could be recompiled every time, writing to disk only as necessary, while weblog pages would only be checked for existence, not changes, before compiling. This still makes me a bit uneasy, but I already have to treat the weblog section as a special case as far as directory index building, so it shouldn't be too big of an issue to set this up. Wowaname also suggested adding a flag that tells the compile script to override the normal weblog page detector and recompile a specific page.

I've been avoiding uploading this website's code out of lack of a decent Git host. However, as wowaname had offered to take a look at the code, I decided to upload it anyway. I don't like Github, because the software they use to host is nonfree, but I already have an account that I use for pull requests to Minetest and bug reports to other projects. I've uploaded the source code there, for the time being. Wowaname says that she plans to start a Git-hosting service that runs on free software though, so once that is up, I will move my code there.

Through a fairly-mundane series of events, I now have a new pseudonym: Larry Talb. Yst Dawson will of course remain my main name, but I might pull Larry on occasion.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Telephony is obsolete

Day 00203: Saturday, 2015 September 26

I don't know why, but my mother asked me to call U-Haul by telephone to get some prices. She knows very well that I always find a non-telephone way to retrieve information. I simply can't stand making unnecessary telephone calls. But more importantly for today, she knows that the only telephone at my disposal is a land line, the land line at home that saves us one cent each moth on our cable bill, a line that we wouldn't even have if it was costing us anything. As we were away from home, I could not reach that telephone and had no way to carry out her request.

As she should have expected, I hit the Web to get the information she wanted. The U-Haul website is set up very stupidly though. The automated system will not give you a price unless you specify a location you are renting from, a location you are returning the rented parts to, and a date upon which you wish to carry out the rental. The first two seem reasonable, and actually effect the price, but there's no reason to need to pick a date. As I am not the one choosing the date, I wasn't able to give an honest answer to the date question, and I couldn't be 100% sure that the date wasn't needed. So, I contacted U-Haul Web support. Again, no telephone needed. I'm not sure why people, especially my mother, insist that *anything* need be carried out by telephone. Web support did not even ask for a date of rental, and best of all, there was no need to try to remember the prices long enough to write them down, try to keep up with what the customer support representative was saying as I try to write down what was just said, ask the representative to pause a bit so I could take notes, or struggle to make out what was being said over a potentially-poor connection. Instead, I was able to wait until the representative left and copy the log containing everything that was said directly to my notes. In what way does that not completely trump telephony as a method of information retrieval? I honestly don't understand why anyone would choose to use a telephone when when this is so much easier.

Hover support wrote back, saying that they could not find my account, so I should give them my user name to help them locate it. They also said that a telephone number is mandatory for use of their services. I gave them the user name and reiterated that I do not have a telephone, then asked if that means that they are unable to sell me domains. Hopefully they will write back and I'll see what becomes of the situation.

We left for home, but I forgot two things in Springfield. First, I left behind the power strip I had wanted to bring home to use with my new desktop computer setup. Once I have a power strip, I'll be able to set up my old server as a desktop workstation. Second, I left behind the hat I wore when I left Coos Bay. Luckily, I have other hats, but that one is my favorite. I'll get it back soon enough though, I'm sure.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Taxes

Day 00204: Sunday, 2015 September 27

Due to the data loss issues bringing me lots of stress in February, I didn't get my taxes filed as soon as I usually do. After that, miscommunication between my mother and I prevented me from getting my taxes at least filed on time. I filed for an extension by mail on the last day before the deadline.

After filing for an extension, I both fell into a bit of a slump and got busy. However, the extended deadline now approaches, so I need to get moving on my tax filing. I wanted to file by mail, due to not having a way to efile directly with the government. I didn't want to go through a third party to file my taxes. However, I'm still very busy, so I've decided to file through a company or two this year. I've requested a PIN from the government for efiling purposes, but I spent much of the day out of the house, so that's as far as I got. Perhaps tomorrow, I will actually fill out the paperwork.

Short of another disaster, I will be filing in February next year, as I normally do.

When we were out shopping today, my mother asked how important it is that I avoid milk. She asked if my milk allergy was really so bad that I needed to avoid a product even if milk was the very last item on the ingredients list. I had to explain once again that first of all, it doesn't take a whole lot of milk to have a very negative effect on my mental state. This can manifest as either depression (if milk is ingested long-term) or headaches (if only a small amount of milk is ingested once). And second, my allergy is only tangentially related to my choice to become vegan. When I went vegan, my allergy symptoms went away, exposing the fact that I even had an allergy. However, if I had not chosen to go vegan, I would have never known about my allergy to milk. Finding out about my allergy did not cause me to go vegan, but vice versa.

I don't understand her. Sometimes she tells me off about being vegan, saying that my reasons are stupid. She says that the environment is not worth it, and that I should just relax about the damage I would be doing by eating and animal products (she doesn't even register the fact that I don't use non-food animal products either). Other times, she forgets my motives altogether, seeming to think my milk allergy has something to do with it. At that point, she tries to get me to think that slight amounts of milk are fine or tries to get me on board with the idea of taking milk-allergy treatment pills so that milk can be on my menu again. I hope that one day she will be able to accept the truth.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The Republic of Cabo Verde

Day 00207: Wednesday, 2015 September 30

The Republic of Cabo Verde's registry got back to me today, sending the user name needed to log in with. It seems the system works, there's just a bit of a delay.

Seeking more words to feed into eschalot, I took a look at /usr/share/dict/ on my system. There are four files there. american-english is a huge word list. The first is a document explaining how to set your default word list. The other three are supposed to be word lists, but american-english is the only actual word list. words.pre-dictionaries-common is just a symbolic link to american-english and words is a symbolic link to /etc/dictionaries-common/words, which in turn is a symbolic link back to american-english. Having only one word list available, I opened the american-english file only to find that many of the words use non-English accents, such as the word "Ångström". These words would not do well in eschalot, so I had grep sort out everything that was not usable, and fed the remaining list to eschalot.

I noticed a couple things with eschalot's handling of word lists. First, eschalot does not understand any word shorter than eight characters. I confirmed this by attempting to use the -l flag to specify that shorter words be used; any lower bound that is shorter than eight characters halts the program, showing the usage instructions. Second, eschalot stops after finding a single word in the list; it does not attempt to create a better onion by stringing multiple random words together. I first tried to fix this by using the included worgen utility to find every combination of words available, but that quickly started filling up my hard drive and I had to abandon that plan. Next, I built a script that lower cased every word on the list, then built a regular expression of of them. I figured if I could compact the words into a single expression, I could just run "eschalot -r '^({expression})+$'", but that didn't work out either. Eschalot complained that the argument list was too long. I tried hacking away at the world list, removing short words and such, but I got to the point where I was removing way too much long before I hit something eschalot could process.

While I was still on the first stage of onion finding, searching using the word list that had the words containing Unicode characters striped out, I ended up with a fairly-usable onion: //unseatedaltleuhs.onion. I don't know what an "altleuh" is, but it's pronounceable, and amusing this bogus word is a noun, it makes sense that some of them might be unseated. I briefly considered using it as a surname instead of "Dawson", but quickly rejected that idea.

ICANN and eNom have been hassling wowaname about her use of an invalid mailing address in her whois record for a name she has registered under a gTLD. They want her to add a verifiable postal address, so I offered her the use of mine so she wouldn't have to divulge her own location. After all, I'm already in the whois database, I've got nothing to hide. SHe took me up on my offer, so I am now authorized to receive mail on Opal Hart's behalf. According to ICANN rules, that makes my address valid for use in her whois records. Her email address, which was only invalid accidentally, has also been corrected, so all that leaves it the incorrect telephone number. I'm hoping that they do not hassle her about that as well.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.